<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AnubhavSaini</title>
    <description>This site belongs to Anubhav Saini. A polyglot programmer, who likes law, science, movies, technology, software...
</description>
    <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 15:44:33 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 15:44:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things I am already hating about rust.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I like a different programming languages because they can do different things and things differently. So, when I look at rust, it looks like same old C language with some C++ code thrown in it. I do not like this language based on it’s looks. What it does is matter of gaining some knowledge in it, which will come later and with time.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s the list of things I hate about &lt;code&gt;rust&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use of &lt;code&gt;::&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use of &lt;code&gt;println&lt;/code&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;if you are outputting something to standard output, please call it &lt;code&gt;stdout()&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;println()&lt;/code&gt; or use &lt;code&gt;out(std, &quot;&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;. You might not be printing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use of main() as entry for program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What year is this? Let functions be functions and allow function writer to choose if the current function should be a entry point or not. Example follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fn first_function() {
	possible_entry(&quot;default&quot;, &quot;ff&quot;, &quot;first_function&quot;);
	out(std, &quot;Hello, World!&quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 15:03:03 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/rust/2015/10/19/Things-I-alread-dislike-about-rust.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/rust/2015/10/19/Things-I-alread-dislike-about-rust.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        <category>rust</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>rust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First rust program and comparison with C.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to say hello, world! in rust too. In C this is very simple and throughly known.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;c&quot;&gt;C&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;  

void main() {  
	printf(&quot;Hello, World!&quot;);  
}  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;fn main() {  
	println!(&quot;Hello, World!&quot;);  
}  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-to-build-binary&quot;&gt;How to build binary?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save file as &lt;code&gt;file_name.rs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;rustc file_name.rs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;run &lt;code&gt;file_name.exe&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;./file_name&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;example-build&quot;&gt;Example build&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blog/2015-10-19-Rust-Program-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that’s odd. It’s exactly the same. I mean look-wise. Let’s find the similarities first and then differences.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;similarities&quot;&gt;Similarities&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both take a string inside double quotes.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both have main() as their starting function.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Both use parenthesis { and } for block delineation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;differences&quot;&gt;Differences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;fn&lt;/code&gt; marks a function in rust.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If returning nothing, we do not need to specify it in rust.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In rust, we do not need to include a file for something as trivial as printing to screen.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In rust, println is a macro whereas in c it is a function.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, if you find a mistake, please let me know so that I can correct it.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 14:52:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/rust/2015/10/19/First-Rust-Program.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/rust/2015/10/19/First-Rust-Program.html</guid>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        <category>rust</category>
        
        <category>c</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>rust</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote of the day.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;QuoteContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quote&quot;&gt;
Winners don&#39;t do different things, they do things differently.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quoter&quot;&gt;Shiv Khera&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 14:50:59 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/19/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/19/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</guid>
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>motivational</category>
        
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anti Pattern - Analysis Paralysis.</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-state-of-over-thinking-a-situation&quot;&gt;A state of over-thinking a situation.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programmers do it. Software Managers do it. Chess robots do it. Teenage girls do it. Recently turned vampires do it. Human rights advocate do it. Procrastinators do it. Mothers do it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;decision-makers-do-not-do-it&quot;&gt;Decision makers do not do it.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very simple and wide-spread phenomenon. You have to make a decision; but you have a lot of data or information; before you could make a decision, you want more time to process or more information to aid you in making that decision. It takes so much time that it feels to others that you have got paralysis. That’s what analysis paralysis or paralysis by analysis is all about.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually we want to make good decisions. But, when fear creeps in, we sort of want to defer the decision making; as if you will be able to find better solution, perhaps the best one.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When problem stays intact and we have consumed a lot of time in making a decision, we have got paralysis by analysis.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In software development this happens almost everytime management wants to design best product. This usually results in long design phases, planning phases, requirement gathering phase and research phase. When bureaucracy creeps in and wants to work as to please the above sitting manager and top management, the analysis phase can go very long as to justify for the future product. Such a product, even before getting started to be built, builds up a huge baggage that can bog down the entire project.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-an-anti-pattern-though&quot;&gt;Why an anti-pattern though?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is called an anti-pattern because it is a pattern and it is anti progress. Anytime you see talk and no walk, think paralysis by analysis.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any debate, discussion, argument over an upcoming controversial policy is analysis paralysis. What should be done is debates, discussions and arguments constructed against or in favor of current/acting/active policies. Then, anybody can see the outcome and tweak the policy and thus output.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such policies are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abortion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Population Control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drug control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patent control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;et cetra.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should be understood already is that all policies are flawed and thus everyone should be working to improve the current policies. Also, no policy should be set in stone. That’s just stupid.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paralysis by analysis can be discouraged by keeping an eye on the goal and current work. Ask yourself, repeatedly, is what you are doing getting you near your goal? If answer is not yes, don’t panic. It might take you there in the longer run; kind of like you have to pull an arrow back to make it hit the target. You get the gist.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ask-yourself---is-what-you-are-doing-helping-you-solve-the-problem-you-are-trying-to-solve-can-it-help-in-longer-run-to-solve-that-problem&quot;&gt;Ask yourself - Is what you are doing helping you solve the problem you are trying to solve? Can it help in longer run to solve that problem?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, do work emails help you out in working work? The answer is probably no. Aren’t those just memes most of the time or spam?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does taking naps in afternoon post-lunch help you work better? The answer is probably yes.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if a management forces you to read spam emails, and doesn’t let you nap, is it worth working for? The answer is probably what you know.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not over think. Break problem in smaller pieces, and start working on one of them. String together all such pieces and you would have solved your problem.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Choose your goals. Once picked, do not alter them.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Reduce your options drastically. Do not even think about trying everything.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Believe that whatever you pick will be a wrong choice, and you’d have to work with it.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get other’s help. Do not hesistate to ask a person sitting right next to you. Even if someone doesn’t know the context of your problem, they might be able to help you out.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Think, not obsess.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Allocate time for the thinking process.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Gather data, not obsessive amount of it.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pick quickly; leave smartness for phones.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be ready for life; deal with problems as they appear. Trying to solve problems when they are not even there is a can of worms, best not opened.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be curious, but not too much. Remember, curiosity killed the cat.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t be a perfectionist. You can perfect yourself, but only in one thing per life.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make a rule book of rules that you do not want to break through out your life. Do not like pasta, don’t have to; do not think over it while ordering italian. Do not like stripes; do not stay in section that hangs stripes. Go to rules for decision making and follow them.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not buy costly stuff that you really don’t need. An SSD for browsing internet, stupid. A MS SQL Serer instance when SQLite will do, stupid. A 56 inch plasma TV when 32 inch one will do, stupid and regretful.  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The End.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analysis_paralysis&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curiosity_killed_the_cat&quot;&gt;For curiosity killed the cat&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice:_Why_More_Is_Less&quot;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice:_Why_More_Is_Less&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 02:40:59 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/patterns/anti-pattern/2015/10/18/Anti-Pattern-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/patterns/anti-pattern/2015/10/18/Anti-Pattern-1.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>patterns</category>
        
        <category>anti-pattern</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>analysis</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>patterns</category>
        
        <category>anti-pattern</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote of the day.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;QuoteContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quote&quot;&gt;
One of the huge mistakes people make is that they try to force an interest on themselves. You don’t choose your passions; your passions choose you.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quoter&quot;&gt;Jeff Bezos&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2015 02:30:59 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/18/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/18/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</guid>
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>motivational</category>
        
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Am Dying.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m dying, so is everybody else. People die. Organic matter decays. There’s science behind it. But I might be dying faster. That warrants some worries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi I am Anubhav Saini - a human being who was given name Anubhav by his parents; Saini being the name of the clan.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a name given to an object that had consciousness. I was even when born felt my surroundings, thus the name given. People give name to consciousness. They do not go on to name rocks. That’s just stupid.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes yes, people have given names to Planets, Rivers and Mountains and ships and what not. But that’s because of Anthropomorphicisation of these objects.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People feel familiarity if name is given; associate things with it; associate feelings with it. That’s why no one names their kid ‘Pran’ or ‘Ravan’ any more. But there are about 10 million Ram running around.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway my reproducers gave me an identity for the world to differentiate me from others. Well, that has worked one sided and wonderfully. I on the other hand have failed to utilize this single opportunity and differentiate myself from world myself. I have failed in that contest.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was I stupid? Am I stupid? People will answer yes and no depending upon who you ask. I’d say, I am not stupid. I just do not have control over my mind.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmm, I do not have control over mind. Who does? Think about mind as a parasite that forced humanoids to have bigger upward pump than available so that it can work better. Mind sucks so much nutrients and energy that if provided it can generate enough wealth for you so that you can feed it with more nutrients and energy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a perfect symbiotic relationship. Mine is just screwed up. I do not want more energy, more nutrients and more money. I just want peace. But that’s not going to happen.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See, I have fungal sinusitis - my doctors told me 5 years ago that. Then they operated on me. I stayed 2 and half years good and then one day my room mate lit a cigarrette and I started dying again. It clogged my sinuses very fast. I am not sure If I can sue him. I could if I was in US or UK, but in India it will take aweful lot of years to wind up.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got a job and cold, AC made me shiver. I had to quit from that job. Then I had to take another job. I was feeling good again. My life was not a ridiculous waste of time anymore. I had purpose to get up in the moring and take a bath. I have always had a purpose to get up and work, it’s bath that I had no reason before to take. Anyway, I learned that when under pressure, if I sleep on my left side, my eye, left one, will fill up with blood. I went to doctors, in a big hospital near diamond district. They wouldn’t listen to me. I told them that I was dying. They wouldn’t listen. I told them that blood in eye + vomiting makes a good reason to be tested. They wouldn’t listen. I wanted them to test me, not treat me for what I thought what was wrong with me; just test me and figure out from there. Anyway, they didn’t perform any tests on me. I was fired from that job for under-performing after a while.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I should sue that hospital, but then, years it would take…  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to realize that my problems are here to stay forever and I will be an under performer forever. I can live with that. But then, I was stung by an insect, it was not a bee or other familiar stinging insect, it was green and was crushed into a plop rather than it’s exosceleton being crushed. What happens when you get bit by an insect and run to a doctor? You get sleep-inducing but anti-allergy medicine. You take it. It hurts a lot. So you take more of these.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when you take a lot of such medicine and while cleaning your nose with Jal-Neti?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, huge chunks of collected, dried out nasal mucousa (sounds like furiosa’s brother) comes out. I mean huge. I mean multiple chunks.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after a few days of spraying small chunks in nose-blow, it stopped. My sinusitis was gone. I could blow my nose clear and breathe properly.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All was well, until yesterday. My nose clogged at once. Couldn’t breathe anymore from nose. My head started hurting. I took one dose that was lying around. After 4 hours another huge chunk came out of it.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should have been relief but what happens when you take anti-allergy medicine that has drowsyness as one of it’s side effects?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, you sleep. A lot.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to wake up and do stuff. I do not work, because I cannot but boy do I keep myself busy!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various coursera courses keep me busy.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind told me that I cannot continue working and have to sleep. I am a consciousness that has it’s own identity. I am not my mind but a chosen subset of it. My mind knows that there are infinite roles I can take. I can be a murderer, a suicider, or a suicide bomber - the last one combines the first two. My mind knows that I can become a doctor or a surgeon or an engineer - actually I am. My mind knows that it can handle complex tasks as writing and book keeping pretty well. But, I on the other hand am a subset of my mind. I do not confirm what my mind knows. My mind can know anything, but I as a conscience inside my mind, have to refrain from becoming anything.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Anubhav Saini. I am dying. So, are you. I want to tell world what I am and not what it sees as what I am. I am better than what I have let world see. But I have physical boundaries. So, does everyone else. Mine are shrinking pretty fast. I am sitting and watching as my degenerative brain degenerates; I can comprehend it. It’s not enough for people around me to recognise it. I have strong will to not let that happen. But, it’s bothering me. Keeping me from actively doing what I can do.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Anubhav Saini and I am dying; whether you care or not. I want to act as a sane person does. But is there any sanity in the world?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People think that they are in control. Are they?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has anyone been in control? Ever? What does that feel like? Have they controlled other human beings? What does that feel like?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has anyone recovered from what I am facing? A severe pain in head that feels like a cluster-headache - it runs for days and hurts like hell. What sort of life do I have? Is it what I was given? Bad genes and bad environment. Did I do this to me?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are my habits bad that they stop me from doing what matters. I do not like to work for stupid people. But aren’t people sitting on top are all stupid. They are so far from reality of low level that their decisions make no sense. Am I not stupid for not working for money?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am I crazy?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone has any clue what they are? I am a chemical bag that has a neural network sitting at top, puppeteering small puppets in the bag. It’s like a musical device: Drink coffee, a different tempo; eat butter a different tempo; eat sleep-inducing anti-allergy medicines - a different tempo. Is the spelling of tempo right?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we put in our body goes to work, some times early, some times late. Chemicals have a profound affect on our bodies. I can drink H2O but not H2O2. The difference is very small in both. One is practically water, other is. One has only one Oxygen and other has two of them. More is not better in this case. Less is more.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to scream that I do not like to put chemicals in my body. My DNA, flawed wants them. My flawed genes require outside help. I cannot continue with stupid morbid gene-pool.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I think about it, I am the first child of my parents. My parents that comprise a female and a male, otherwise lovingly called mother and father. My mother’s side have this bad genetic disorder that affects brain. I think it skips some, but it is there. For example, one of the brothers of my mother’s father was a lunatic. He had degenerated brain disease. My mother’s brother’s son has is a bad egg too. He has a degenerated brain. Impaired learning and bad cognitive skills. I do not have have learning disability but I cannot know that for sure. I am me. Someone who knows more about learning has to tell. I can tell you that new information hurts my head. That’s why I do not like surprises well. That’s why learning new stuff makes my head hurt and I sort of refrain from it. That’s why I am a slow implementer. That’s why…  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait a minute, I and my cousin are both the first child. I do not know if the degenerate grand-father (brother of grandfather), was first child or not. I am leaving space for this information for updation purposes. (Space that will be updated if he was first child or not)  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can there be a disease that affects only the first kid?  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With skipping and gene variation, it might have small affect on me. Undetectably small perhaps. Small enough to write-up as personality (or personality disorder) by anyone who comes in my contact. But what if it is really a genetic disorder?   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am Anubhav Saini. I am dying. I hope to write more about it before I kick the bucket though.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, bye bye. Come back for more real-life-tragedy-description, later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 20:39:59 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/morbid/2015/10/17/I-Am-Dying.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/morbid/2015/10/17/I-Am-Dying.html</guid>
        
        <category>death</category>
        
        <category>morbid</category>
        
        <category>un-motivational</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>morbid</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to life!</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipes are clogged again, call a plumber.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after a few weeks of clear sinuses, I got the bad news yesterday - It’s clogged again.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I am going back to sleeping a lot - a side-effect of anti-histamine drugs that I am about to begin taking again, and running salty water through nose - jal neti procedure. I think I’d be just fine, sleepy, slept, sleepy still, but just fine.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks fungal-sinusitis. I really deserve a kick in head so often.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[crying face]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing much, reading Mathematics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 15:59:58 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//news/2015/10/17/Welcome-Back-To-Life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//news/2015/10/17/Welcome-Back-To-Life.html</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote of the day.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;QuoteContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quote&quot;&gt;
Don’t focus on the victory, focus on the task.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quoter&quot;&gt;Coach Erik Spoelstra&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 05:55:50 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/17/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/17/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</guid>
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>motivational</category>
        
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Quote of the day.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;QuoteContainer&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quote&quot;&gt;
A &lt;span class=&quot;emphasis&quot;&gt;good plan violently executed now&lt;/span&gt; is better than a perfect plan executed next week.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;Quoter&quot;&gt;George Patton&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 15:40:10 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/16/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//daily/quotes/2015/10/16/Quote-Of-The-Day.html</guid>
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
        <category>motivational</category>
        
        
        <category>daily</category>
        
        <category>quotes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Solar system.</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;SolarSystem&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img id=&quot;sun&quot; src=&quot;/images/blog/solar-system/sun.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;mercury-orbit&quot; title=&quot;Mercury&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;mercury&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;venus-orbit&quot; title=&quot;Venus&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div id=&quot;venus&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div id=&quot;earth-orbit&quot; title=&quot;Earth&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img id=&quot;earth&quot; src=&quot;/images/blog/solar-system/earth.png&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:08:58 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/web/2015/10/16/Solar-System.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://iamanubhavsaini.github.io//blog/programming/web/2015/10/16/Solar-System.html</guid>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
        <category>HTML</category>
        
        <category>CSS</category>
        
        <category>css-animations</category>
        
        <category>solar-system</category>
        
        <category>code</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
        <category>web</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
